Jack: A Backend developer is a person
who builds and maintains the technology
needed for to make sure that data or
services requested by the front end
system or software, are delivered.
They use their understanding of
programming languages and tools to solve
problems and their responsibilities may
involve creating, maintaining, testing,
and debugging the ‘back end’ which allows
the software or hardware to function.
To be a Backend developer it is
often a requirement to have a BA in
computer science or another closely
related field and have worked their
way up from a more junior role.
Backend developers need good technological
skills and are often well versed in
several different programming languages.
See below to learn more about this role.